変数のスコープとは
変数が有効なコード内における範囲のことです。
コード内でスコープの中にある変数のことを
ローカル変数と呼びます。
コード群は一般的に、変数のスコープを
定義するもので、それらは中括弧によって
示されます。
例えば、例示されているクラスの
中にあるものは全て、ローカルである
と言うことができます。
pens、crayons、answer 変数は全て
Example 関数のローカルであり、
関数の外側で使用することはできません。
alpha、beta、gamma 変数は
ScopeAndModifiersクラスの
スコープにあると言えます。
そして、pens、crayons、answer 変数は
Example 関数のスコープ
にあると言えます。
Public Private アクセス修飾子
クラスで定義された変数は
関数内で宣言されたものとは違って
アクセス修飾子の特質を持っている
アクセス修飾子というのは、変数を宣言する時に
データ型の前に書くキーワードで、
変数や関数がどこから閲覧できるか
を定義するためにあります。
一般的には、他のスクリプトが変数や関数に
アクセスする必要がある時には public を、
そうで無い時は private にしておくべきです。
public として変数を宣言するのは
クラスの外側からアクセスできる、ということを意味します。
そして、変数が Inspecter のコンポーネント
に表示され、編集もできるということも意味します。
この例では、
ScopeAndAccesModifiersスクリプトは
prop_samoflange オブジェクトに適用されており、
public 変数 alpha が編集可能なプロパティとして
スクリプトに含まれていることが見て取れます。
このことによって、ユーザーがゲームをテストしている
間に変数を編集することができます。
例えば、車の速度を調節する
値があるとします。それがあれば
ゲームを停止し、スクリプトを変更してから
やり直さなくてもテスト中にその変数を
調節できるので便利でしょう。そのように、
public 変数を持つというのは理にかなった
ことなのです。変数がクラス内で
初期値に初期化された場合に
注意してください。例えば、alphaの値を
5に設定したとしても、
Inspector に記述された値に
上書きされたままになります。
しかし、もしこれらの値が
Inspector で設定された後に
Start や Awake といった関数で設定されたら
Inspectorの値には上書きされません。
例えば、スクリプトが初期値に5を
設定されていたとしたのに、
Inspector によって上書きされたものを
Start関数内で手動で設定すると、
Inspectorの値を上書きします。
Now given that the game is at runtime
if I tweak the value again
that's now overriding the script again.
So bear in mind that even though the
public variable is tweakable on the
component it doesn't mean that you can't
go back and edit it via a script during
during runtime.
Private variables can only be edited from
within the class. In C# private is the
default access modifier for any
variable that doesn't have it specified.
So although I've written private on
beta and gamma, if I hadn't they would be
private regardless. It's good practice
to make all member variables, those that belong
to a class rather than a function,
private, unless they need to be public
for a specific reason.
Setting variables and functions to public
can also mean that you can access them from
other scripts. So for example I have
another class here which has 2 functions in,
a public function called FruitMachine
and a private called OfficeSort.
And I have some public variables and
some private variables. Back in my original
script I can call only the public
members of that script.
For example, if I were to create
an instance of the class
AnotherClass, and you can see that when I
try and access this the
apples and banana variables as well as
FruitMachine are available,
and you can see that in telesense in MonoDevelop
is telling me that I can use these.
So when I choose FruitMachine and open the
the bracket it's then telling me what
arguments need to be fed in to that.
And I can feed in any of the variables
that are in scope of this script, or
that are in scope of AnotherClass
because they are public.
So I could use any of the variables
from my scope and access modifiers class
and I can access the instance of another
class and make use of a public variable
from there, such as apples for example.
Note that because the OfficeSort
and stapler and sellotape are all
private I can't access them by creating
an instance of another class.
They're for use only within the class itself.